<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: life | Fugiman]]></title>
  <link href="http://fugiman.github.io/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://fugiman.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-12T16:19:21+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://fugiman.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris "Fugiman" Gamble]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[They say the first step is the hardest...]]></title>
    <link href="http://fugiman.github.io/blog/2013/08/10/they-say-the-first-step-is-the-hardest-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-10T01:49:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fugiman.github.io/blog/2013/08/10/they-say-the-first-step-is-the-hardest-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been a web developer for many years now, and during that time I&rsquo;ve never really had a site of my own.
It always struck me as odd that for someone whose daily routine consisted of making websites, I couldn&rsquo;t even make one for myself.
The sites I made were for a purpose &ndash; they provided a service or a piece of information &ndash; and I couldn&rsquo;t figure out what the purpose of a personal site would be.
Last year I made a single page site as a portfolio, and I was immediately disgusted with it.
I&rsquo;m a developer, not a designer.
The representation of myself as an artist instead of a problem solver just didn&rsquo;t feel right.
So I deleted it and returned to having nothing to say &ldquo;This is me&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Over the past year I&rsquo;ve more firmly integrated myself into the open source world.
I started heavily using github, and began to collaborate with others.
As a part of this process, I found many interesting programmers who were much smarter than me.
They all had one thing in common, they had a blog.
A few days ago, I found a blog post saying that &ldquo;comments are a facade fooling people into thinking they have a voice. They don&rsquo;t. You only have a voice if you have a blog.&rdquo;
While perhaps a bit extreme of a claim, it made me realize that comments are much like posting anonymously: It&rsquo;s very unlikely that people will use it to build an image of you.
Your comments are spread over many websites, sometimes with different usernames.
It&rsquo;s hard for people to build them into a complete picture of you, unless they are the NSA.
A blog, on the other hand, is a monolithic compendium of who you are.
If somebody reads your blog, they can build an image of the kind of person you are.
Perhaps a flawed and incomplete image, but an image nonetheless.</p>

<p>And there I had my answer.
A portfolio is silly, I can just link you to what I&rsquo;ve made.
After all, they are websites.
A blog is the way for me to actually share the struggles I have, what I learn from them, and hopefully I can teach you something as well.
And just maybe, it&rsquo;ll lead to me being a better programmer.
I look forward to seeing what comes of it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
